{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The accepted hypothesis for DNA replication is", "opta": "conservative theory", "optb": "dispersive theory", "optc": "semi-conservative theory", "optd": "evolutionary theory", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When DNA polymerase is in contact with guanine in the parental strand, what does it add to the growing daughter strand?", "opta": "Phosphate", "optb": "Cytosine", "optc": "Uracil", "optd": "Guanine", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Telomeres are usually rich in which nucleotide?", "opta": "Adenine", "optb": "Guanine", "optc": "Thymine", "optd": "Cytosine", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the largest among the followings?", "opta": "Nucleotide", "optb": "Nitrogenous base", "optc": "Phosphate", "optd": "Carbon", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The chromosomal DNA complexes with", "opta": "three types of histone as H1, H2A and H4", "optb": "five types of histone as H1, H2A, H2B, H3 and H4", "optc": "four types of histone as H1, H2A, H3 and H4", "optd": "two types of histone as H1 and H4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Taylor, Woods and Hughes labeled Vicia DNA by allowing new DNA synthesis in the presence of radioactive thymine. After DNA replication (S phase of the cell cycle), it was observed that", "opta": "only one chromatid of a chromosome was labeled", "optb": "both chromatids of a chromosome were labeled", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "neither chromatid was labeled", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In DNA double helix, the two DNA chains are held together by", "opta": "covalent bonds between the pair of bases", "optb": "hydrogen bonds between the pair of bases", "optc": "ionic bonds between the pair of bases", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 5' and 3' numbers are related to the", "opta": "length of the DNA strand", "optb": "carbon number in sugar", "optc": "the number of phosphates", "optd": "the base pair rule", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Messelsen and Stahl model of replication was called", "opta": "conservative replication", "optb": "semi-conservative replication", "optc": "dispersive replication", "optd": "Cri du Chat", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most common liquid volumes in molecular biology are measured in", "opta": "ml", "optb": "\u03bcl", "optc": "nl", "optd": "1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNA replication takes place in which direction?", "opta": "3' to 5'", "optb": "5 'to 3'", "optc": "Randomly", "optd": "Vary from organism to organism", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNA gyrase in E. coli", "opta": "adds positive supercoils to chromosomal DNA", "optb": "can be inhibited with antibiotics", "optc": "is required only at the oriC site", "optd": "performs the same function as helicase in eukaryotes", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In DNA, there are", "opta": "five bases known as adenine, guanine, thymine, tryptophan and cytosine", "optb": "four bases known as adenine, guanine, thymine and cytosine", "optc": "three bases known as adenine, guanine and cytosine", "optd": "only two bases known as adenine and cytosine", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In DNA, guanine pairs with", "opta": "Adenine", "optb": "Cytosine", "optc": "Thymine", "optd": "Uracil", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is incorrect?", "opta": "In DNA double helix, two strands of the DNA are bound with each other with the bases", "optb": "Adenine always pairs with thymine", "optc": "Guanine always pairs with the cytosine", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the only common methylation in the DNA of eukaryotes?", "opta": "Adenosine in GpA dinucleotides", "optb": "Guanosine in ApGpA trinucleotides", "optc": "Cytosine in CpG dinucleotides", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNAs when charged, migrate in a gel towards the", "opta": "positive pole", "optb": "negative pole", "optc": "will not migrate", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the approximate size (in kb) of the E. coli genome?", "opta": "3000 kilobase", "optb": "4500 kilobase", "optc": "5500 kilobase", "optd": "6500 kilobase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the study of one experiment it was found that the value of Tm for DNA is = 40\u00b0 C. If the cell has 20% GC at the above Tm, then what will be value of 'Tm' if the GC% increases to 60%?", "opta": "Remains same", "optb": "Increases", "optc": "Decreases", "optd": "Can not be compared", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the range of melting point temperatures (Tm) for most DNA molecules?", "opta": "50 to 60\u00b0C", "optb": "60 to 80\u00b0C", "optc": "70 to 90\u00b0C", "optd": "80 to l00\u00b0C", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The overall conclusion of the Hershey-Chase experiment was that", "opta": "DNA was responsible for heredity", "optb": "proteins and DNA were responsible for heredity", "optc": "the ratio of Adenine to thymine was always the same", "optd": "phage DNA was similar to bacterial DNA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A cesium chloride will separate DNA molecules by", "opta": "absorption", "optb": "resorption", "optc": "density", "optd": "adhesion", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If one cell has AT contents 40%, what will be the percentage of Guanine residue?", "opta": "60%", "optb": "15%", "optc": "30%", "optd": "Guanine residue can not be calculated", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following enzyme adds complementary bases during replication?", "opta": "Helicase", "optb": "Synthesase", "optc": "Replicase", "optd": "Polymerase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which DNA polymerase removes RNA primers in DNA synthesis?", "opta": "Polymerase I", "optb": "Polymerase II", "optc": "Polymerase III", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Enzymes, responsible for unraveling short segments of DNA is", "opta": "DNA polymerase", "optb": "helicase", "optc": "DNA ligase", "optd": "primase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Enzyme, responsible for proofreading base pairing is", "opta": "DNA polymerase", "optb": "Telomerase", "optc": "Primase", "optd": "DNA ligase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following would not contain DNA?", "opta": "Yeast", "optb": "Bacteria", "optc": "Glass crystals", "optd": "Mold", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The nucleosome consists of histone", "opta": "octamer and 146 bp of DNA", "optb": "tetramer and 146 bp of DNA", "optc": "hexamer and 146 bp of DNA", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What bands will be observed in a cesium chloride gradient after two rounds of replication?", "opta": "One light, one medium and one heavy band", "optb": "One light and one medium band", "optc": "One medium band", "optd": "One medium and one heavy band", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Proteins involved in opening a replication bubble are", "opta": "DNA helicases", "optb": "single stranded binding proteins", "optc": "ligase", "optd": "DNA topoisomerase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the main damaging effect of UV radiation on DNA?", "opta": "Depurination", "optb": "Formation of thymine dimers", "optc": "Single strand break", "optd": "Dehydration", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The higher order structure of DNA shows symmetry, whereas the higher order structures of most proteins do not. Why isn't protein shape more regular like DNA?", "opta": "DNA has one main function in cells whereas proteins have many.", "optb": "The many different amino acid R groups on proteins confer many different shapes.", "optc": "Some S amino acids cause proteins to bend; others cause protein to flatten.", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNA helicase is used to", "opta": "unwind the double helix", "optb": "interact the double helix closely", "optc": "break a phosphodiester bond in DNA strand", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Klenow fragment without free nucleotides exhibits", "opta": "exonuclease activity", "optb": "endonuclease activity", "optc": "nickase activity", "optd": "no activity", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "E.coli DNA polymerases II and III lack", "opta": "5' \u2192 3' exonuclease activity", "optb": "5' \u2192 3' endonuclease activity", "optc": "partially 5' \u2192 3' exonuclease activity", "optd": "partially 5' \u2192 3' endonuclease activity", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In sperm heads, DNA is particularly highly condensed and the histones are replaced with small basic protein called", "opta": "protamines", "optb": "purines", "optc": "pyrimidines", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Okazaki fragments occur during", "opta": "transformation", "optb": "replication", "optc": "polymerase reaction", "optd": "synthesis", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNA can be sequenced by the", "opta": "chemical method", "optb": "chain termination procedure", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "physical method", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which histone(s) are associated with the linker DNA of a nucleosome?", "opta": "Histone H1", "optb": "Histones H2A and H2B", "optc": "Histone H3", "optd": "Histone H4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}